# **Christopher Albanese**

| Front End Developer

Christopher@CafeRE.com

Orlando, FL

m: 212.203.1091

## **Professional Summary**

With extensive experience in business development, marketing and education, Chris brings a deep understanding that code flows from keyboards to customers, and how the requirements of the business and its stakeholders ultimately need to intersect with the needs of the client. This fuels his appreciation for user-driven development.

### **Technical Skills**

Front End: JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS, SASS (SCSS), JSX, Swift, Markdown, Wordpress, jQuery,

Bootstrap, Emotion JS.

**Back End:** Express, Mongo DB, Node JS, Mongoose

OS/Software: macOS, Windows, Visual Studio Code, Atom, Xcode, Git & Github, Photoshop, fileMaker

Pro, Glitch, CodeSandbox.io, MS Office

### Relevant Experience

#### www.ChristopherAlbanese.com - 2018 - present

A Personal portfolio site designed to showcase recent projects and certifications. This was built using React v16 with Gatsby v2 and styled with CSS-in-JS using the Emotion-JS library.

#### www.RECalcApp.com - Jan 2017 - Nov 2017

An iOS app for Real Estate Professionals, to assist with common math and date calculations. This was built in Xcode using Swift 4, UIKit, CocoaPods and incorporates ads using AdMob from Google.

#### www.RealEstateAcademyofOrlando.com – June 2016 – Present

An online real estate school built on WordPress with WooCommerce and incorporating payment gateways from Square and PayPal.

### **Certificates:** FCC | FreeCodeCamp.org

(Approximately 300 hours per certificate)

Responsive Web Design: HTML, CSS, Visual Design, A11Y, Responsive Design Principles, CSS Flexbox,

CSS Grid, User Story Projects

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures:

JavaScript, ES6, Regular Expressions, Debugging, Data Structures, Algorithm Scripting, OOP, Functional Programming, Intermediate

Algorithm Scripting, User Story Projects

Front End Libraries: Bootstrap, ¡Query, SASS, React, Redux, React & Redux, User Story Projects

**Data Visualization:** Data Visualization with D3.js, JSON APIs and Ajax, User Story Projects

APIs and Microservices: Managing Packages with NPM, Basic Node and Express, MongoDB and

Mongoose, APIs and Microservices Projects

**Education** 

University of Florida: Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration

University of S. Florida: Associate of Arts